<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sketches on VirtualDataSet</title>
    <link>http://docs.virtdata.io/sketches/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sketches on VirtualDataSet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>APL 2.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://docs.virtdata.io/sketches/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Function Graph Kernel API</title>
      <link>http://docs.virtdata.io/sketches/function_graph_kernel_api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.virtdata.io/sketches/function_graph_kernel_api/</guid>
      <description>The functional graph kernel API is simply the implementation of a function graph, as realized in your application. This is the result of binding a parsed function graph template to a set of functions within a graph.
What makes the functional kernel useful are the various ways that you can interact with it. This is defined by the API.
Setting coordinates Whe a functional kernel is realized in your runtime, it will have a set of named inputs which we call coordinates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Sketches</title>
      <link>http://docs.virtdata.io/sketches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 21:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.virtdata.io/sketches/</guid>
      <description>This section holds design sketches of some of the more esoteric design elements of EngineBlock.
 Function Graph Kernel  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FGK Sketch</title>
      <link>http://docs.virtdata.io/sketches/function_graph_kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://docs.virtdata.io/sketches/function_graph_kernel/</guid>
      <description>This section elaborates on the function graph kernel design.
Consider the following function graph. For the sake of discussion, it is assumed that this is not merely a functiong graph template, but instad a fully realized function graph kernel. In practices, this simply means that all of the function names can be mapped to an actual implementation in a runtime library, and that there is enough detail in the graph to find an unambiguous mapping for such.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>